Hi everyone, I'm Patrick and in this video I show you how I would learn
machine learning if I could start over. For context, I'm a machine learning developer
advocate at assembly AI and before that I worked several years as
software developer and ML engineer and I also teach Python and machine
learning on my own YouTube channel. So I would say I'm pretty experienced
in the field, but I know that the available courses out there
can be overwhelming for beginners, so I hope to give you some guidance with this
video. The demand for machine learning engineers is still increasing every
year, so it's a great skill to have. I divided this learning path
into seven steps that should take you about three months to finish.
Of course, this can vary depending on how much time and effort you want to
put into this, and I know that everyone learns differently or might
have different goals. So this is just my personal take on how
to learn machine learning. You can use this guide if you just want to explore
machine learning as a hobby, but also if you plan to find a job in
the field. I will mention a few more tips about the job search
in the end. So let's jump into the study plan. The first thing I recommend
is to lay the foundation with some math basics. Now you might
say math is not really necessary anymore, and this is partly true.
The available machine learning frameworks abstract the math away
and I know many machine learning engineers so don't need it in their day job
at all. However, in my opinion, knowing the underlying
math provides you with a better foundation and better understanding of how the
algorithms work and it makes your life easier when you run into
problems. Also, I think there is beauty in the underlying
math that makes the machines learn. So for me, knowing the
math sparked my excitement even more. Now you don't need to get too deep
into this. A great website with free resources is Khan
Academy. So my recommendation is just to take some basic courses
and then move on. And then later when you do the actual machine
learning course and don't understand everything, then come back here
and learn the missing topics. Oh, and by the way, you find all the resources
and recommendations recommended courses in the description below. The next step is
to learn Python. It is the number one programming language
for machine learning and there is no way around it. All major machine
learning frameworks are built with it and all major courses use Python
for their exercises. So having decent Python skills is
essential to build machine learning projects. Now, you don't need to become
an advanced software developer, but a little bit more than the beginner level would
be great. One great thing about Python is that it is very beginner
friendly and in my opinion it's the best first programming language
you can learn. I recommend two free courses on YouTube,
one four hour beginner course and one six hour intermediate course
and then you should have a solid base. This step is what I call the
Machine learning tech stack and consists of the most important Python libraries
for machine learning, data science and data visualization. This step is
a bit optional because you can also pick up these skills later when you do
the actual machine learning course, but I think it's great to build the foundation
first and then it will be easier later. The three libraries I recommend
at this point are Numpy, which is the base for everything,
Pandas, which is important for data handling and matplotlib,
which is needed for visualization. These libraries are used in almost every
machine learning project. That's why I would include them in your learning path
at this point. Again, you don't need to learn too much here.
I recommend just following one free crash course for each library
and then later pick up more advanced concepts if you need them.
At this point you don't have to learn the machine learning courses like SciKit,
Learn, TensorFlow or PyTorch. You could of course if you want, but these are
included in the machine learning course. I show you in a moment so you
can pick these up later. Now that we've covered the coding skills,
it is finally time for the actual machine learning course.
There are many great ones available, but the most popular and in my
opinion also one of the best ones is the machine learning specialization
by Andrew Ng on Coursera. This specialization includes three
courses. It got revamped just a few months ago and now includes
Python with numpy, scikit Learn and tensorflow for the code.
So you not only learn all the essential machine learning concepts,
but also get your first hands on experience with the ML libraries.
It is extensive and it takes several weeks to finish, but it's
worth it. After these courses I have one more recommendation for you.
I suggest to implement a few algorithms from scratch in
Python using only Pure Python and NumPy, for example
by following my ML from scratch playlist here on YouTube.
This is completely optional, but it helped me to properly understand understand some
of the concepts from Android's course and a lot of students have told me
the same feedback, so check it out if you want to. Also, we plan to
release an updated version of the ML from Scratch course here
on the Assembly AI channel, so make sure to subscribe to our channel and
don't miss it. Now I recommend getting even more hands on and learning
more about data preparation for this Kaggle has
awesome free courses on their website. I recommend at least the
intro to ML and intermediate ML courses. They are
lightweight compared to the previous one and some material is just a refresher for
you, but you'll learn more about data preprocessing and data preparation
with Pandas. Each lesson has a theory part and then some coding exercises.
It also gives you a gentle introduction to the Kaggle platform and you learn
how to make code submissions on Kaggle, which is perfect for the
next point. Now it's time to practice as much as possible
and apply your knowledge to real world machine learning problems.
For this, the best platform is Kaggle.com it provides
thousands of different data sets and challenges where you can participate.
Participating in challenges can motivate you a lot.
Now I wouldn't try making it to the top or even winning prize money
with this because to be honest, this requires true expertise
and also a lot of GPU power. But I would
still try to tweak your solutions multiple times by
learning more about data pre processing and also about hyperparameter
tuning. You can then use Kaggle competitions to build your portfolio
and put them on your cv. So in my opinion, Kaggle is an awesome
platform and you should practice here as much as possible. Of course, you can
also tackle other machine learning problems outside of Kaggle.
It just makes your life a little bit easier because it provides you with
the datasets, a platform to evaluate the projects, and there's
a whole community around it. At this point you can already be super proud
of yourself. And now in this last section I want to give you a few
more tips if your goal is to get a job. The tasks of ML engineers
vary a lot and it's not possible to know everything. For example, some positions
are specialized in computer vision or nlp, or they
require you to have experience with a specific ML framework or even
MLOps requirements like how to deploy and scale ML apps.
MLOps is a whole field on its own, so I may cover this in a
separate video. My point is you have to decide in which field you
want to work and then look at the requirements in some corresponding job descriptions
and then specialize in this direction. Another great tip I can give
you, and this is something I wish I had done earlier in my career,
is to start a blog. You can write tutorials, share what you've
learned, which projects you have built, which problems you have faced along the
way, and how you've solved them by writing about a topic, you can deepen your
knowledge and then you can use this as a resource on your cv. Trust me,
this will increase your chances to get an interview a lot.
All right, that's my recommendation for a machine learning study guide. Again,
this might not be suited for everyone. This is just how I would learn
machine learning if I had to start over. Just one more quick addition.
If you prefer learning with books, then you can check out these two books.
Let me know in the comments if this was helpful or if you have any
other suggestions you would add to the plan. Don't forget to check
out the resource list I put in the description below and then I hope to
see you in the next video.